# **Matt Cox**

### Advanced practice clinician and marketing professional

Taylors, SC 29687 mattcox7777@gmail.com - 706-372-4822

My previous employment includes practicing nurse anesthesia, marketing and educational public speaking for specific healthcare models throughout the southeast, managing medical/renal floors in a large hospital setting, coordinating practice-specific contracts with insurance companies, hospital administrations, and private physicians as well as direct sales in healthcare. I also have experience with my own billing and CPT-9 coding. Clinically I began practice as a registered nurse in 1998 and a certified registered nurse anesthetist in 2002. I have over ten years of experience in surgery, emergency medicine, OB/GYN, pediatrics, geriatrics, and directing anesthesia services. I have always enjoyed a fast-paced and competitive environment. My experience has allowed me to become comfortable with high acuity and high stress situations. I enjoy interactions with physicians and nurses in these delicate situations. Again, I believe my experience and education provides me an advantage because I have a comprehensive understanding of the clinician and non-clinician aspects of healthcare.

My passion has always rested in helping people and providing quality healthcare. I have a strong work ethic and I believe in providing an example of integrity. I will be fully committed to a position if offered. I would love the opportunity for an interview to discuss this further. Thank you for your time.

Matt Cox

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

#### Temporary Assignment

WorkSmart Staffing - Greenville, SC - June 2015 to Present

Responsibilities

I'm currently working at Sourcelink which is a marketing and advertising company.

#### **Owner**

Cox Landscaping - Lincolnton, GA - January 2006 to December 2014

Responsibilities

Owned and operated landscaping company consisting of ten employees. We handled commercial and residential contracts in central Georgia.

### **Assistant Superintendent**

College Park Golf Course - Atlanta, GA - June 2013 to October 2013

Responsibilities

General golf course management including sales, golf instruction, and grounds maintenance.

#### Volunteer

Talbott Recovery Campus - Atlanta, GA - April 2013 to October 2013

Responsibilities

Assisted new patients and their families with transitioning into a residential substance abuse treatment facility.

#### **Practice Coordinator**

Nationwide Anesthesia - Sandersville, GA - January 2012 to December 2012

Responsibilities

Marketed, advertised, and negotiated office-based full service anesthesia contracts throughout the United States.

### **Clinical Manager**

Doctors Hospital - Augusta, GA - January 2008 to October 2009

Responsibilities

Clinical manager of medical and dialysis unit in a level 2 trauma center. My unit consisted of approximately 25 full and part time employees.

### **Education and Marketing Director (Southeast)**

Joseph M. Still Burn Center - Augusta, GA - November 2006 to January 2008

Responsibilities

I marketed the Burn Center and provided educational seminars to emergency departments, urgent care clinics, and physician offices throughout the southeast.

#### President, Owner

AM Anesthesia, LLC - Martinez, GA - January 2005 to April 2007

Responsibilities

I negotiated and carried out anesthesia contracts to hospital administrations and private physicians in Georgia.

#### **Staff Nurse Anesthetist**

Anesthesia and Pain medicine - Augusta, GA - June 2002 to December 2005

Responsibilities

Staff nurse anesthetist in a level 2 trauma center and the largest burn hospital in the United States.

### **Resident Certified Registered Nurse Anesthetist**

Carolinas Medical Center - Charlotte, NC - January 2000 to May 2002

### Staff RN- Medical Surgical Intensive Care Unit

Columbia - Augusta, GA - July 1998 to December 1999

**EDUCATION** 

### Master's of Science in Anesthesia

University of North Carolina/Carolina's Medical Center - Charlotte, NC 2000 to 2002

### **Bachelor's of Science in Nursing**

Brenau University - Gainesville, GA 1995 to 1998

MILITARY SERVICE

Service Country: United States

Branch: USAR Rank: 2LT

March 2000 to September 2005

Individual Mobilization Augmentee (IMA) Deployments: Fort Sam Houston, San Antonio, Texas Fort Wainwright, Fairbanks, Alaska

Commendations: Honorable Discharge

**CERTIFICATIONS** 

### **ACLS/BLS**

**PUBLICATIONS** 

## Managing peri-operative anxiety in pediatric patients and families alike

May 5, 2002

Research design on the diagnosis and maintenance of minimizing anxiety with the pediatric surgical patient and their associated families. This project was accompanied by a video which details the entire surgical experience from the patient and family perspective starting the night before surgery to the point of being discharged home to normal activity. This project was funded by the University of North Carolina/Carolina's medical center nurse anesthesia program.